Mariana Bayona Terriaga De Almeida

marianabtalmeida@hotmail.com / São Paulo - SP Brazil

Summary

Software engineer with bachelor's degree in Computer Science and extensive experience in Banking and Financial Systems.

Performed migrations of legacy systems and is currently working on PaaS migration of a mission-critical banking system to AWS Cloud, involved in all stages of the software development cycle, from planning and design to testing and deployment, at the biggest bank of Latin America.

Experience

Itaú Unibanco S.A. - Software Engineer

11/2021 - Current

- Migrated microservices from PaaS to AWS Cloud in an Event-driven architecture.
- Collaborated with development team members to create and integrate high availability solutions for mission-critical banking applications.

Itaú Unibanco S.A. - Junior Software Engineer

12/2019 - 11/2021

Brazil

- Migrated a legacy system from mainframe to microservices architecture in PaaS environment.
- Conducted full lifecycle software development from planning to deployment and maintenance.

Itaú Unibanco S.A. - Software Engineer Intern

04/2019 - 12/2019

- Generated efficient, modular and maintainable back-end code.
- Designed and implemented backend models and API endpoints for complex workflows.

Skills

- Amazon Web Services
- Spring Boot
- **REST APIs**
- SOL
- Terraform
- Microservices
- Apache Kafka
- RedHat Openshift
- Databases

Education

12/2019

Pontifícia Universidade Católica de São Paulo

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

Certifications

 Amazon Web Services Certified Cloud Practitioner

Languages

Portuguese: First Language

English:	C1
Advanced	
Spanish:	B1

Intermediate